Guide to the Committee on United States/Latin American Relations printed material, c. 1975-1990.
Committee on United States/Latin American Relations printed material, c. 1975-1990.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Committee on United States/Latin American Relations printed material, c. 1975-1990.
39-6-2796
Committee on United States/Latin American Relations.
19 cubic ft.
Magazines, periodicals, newsletters, articles, reports, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Printed resource materials relating to Latin America collected by CUSLAR, including magazines, periodicals, newsletters, articles, and reports.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Printed resource materials relating to Latin America collected by CUSLAR, including magazines, periodicals, newsletters, articles, and reports.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.
Places:
Latin America--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Nicaragua- correspondence, memos, reports, publications, 1970s-1980s (Box 1)
- Christic Institute Case Iran/Contra (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Pensamicento Propio, 1987-89 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Inter-American Development Bank publications, 1985-91 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Cornell course: Women, "Feminism," and Change in Latin America - taught by Veronica Frenkel, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Theology in Latin America- papers, publications, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Latin America - published material, 1968-79 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Working papers and publications concerning Latin America, 1980s (Box 2)
- United States - Gov. policies (general), 1980s (Box 2, Folder 7)
- United States - gov. policies (AFL-CIO), 1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- United States - Gov. Policies (FBI), 1977-1980s (Box 2, Folder 9)
- United States - Gov. Policies (Low Intensity Conflict), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- United States - Gov. Policies (Alternatives), 1980s (Box 2, Folder 11)
- United States - Gov. Policies (McCarran- Walter Act), 1984-88 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- United States - Gov. Policies (Walker Amendment Travel Restrictions), 1986-88 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- United States - Opposition, 1980s (Box 2, Folder 14)
- United States - Church (Solidarity), 1980s (Box 2, Folder 15)
- United States: Labor (United Farm Workers), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- United States - Cornell Student Activism, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Report submitted to Cornell's BOT - Investments in South Africa, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Congressional Action - correspondence, 1976-78 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- CIA - General Info, 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 20)
- CIA and the Press, 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 21)
- CIA- Nicaragua, 1983-84 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- CIA- Chile, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 23)
- CIA - publications, 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Organizing Notes - publication, 1977-81 (Box 3)
- CIA/FBI- Illegal surveillance, political repression- articles, 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Church in Latin America, 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 2-6)
- Central American Refugees, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 7)
- South American Refugees, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Indigenous People - Solidarity, 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 9)
- United Nations, 1974-76 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- North American Indians - Solidarity, 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Nuestra Lucha - publication, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Central America- Militarization, 1980-84 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Sanctuary Movement, 1985-86 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Church and Solidarity, 1969-87 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Nicaragua Solidarity, 1980s (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Latin America - Solidarity, 1970s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Latin American Women, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Albany Sanctuary, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Sanctuary - Resources (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Sanctuary Cities, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Basta! - Chicago Sanctuary Committee, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Carecen - Central American Refugee Center, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Sanctuary - Southwest U.S. Groups, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Sanctuary - General, 1984-85 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Sanctuary Movement, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Legal Aspects/ Legislation on Sanctuary (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Alejandro, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- CUSLAR Events, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Ithaca as a Sanctuary, 1985-90 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- "Esperanza", 1985-86 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Rochester Sanctuary Committee, 1985-89 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Unions - UWA, FLOC, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Labor Papers, 1977-81 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Union Publications, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Boycott Coors!, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Women - Abortion, 1977-89 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Feminism - Women, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Women - Miscellaneous, 1970s-1980s (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Carasa, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Carasa News, 1978-80 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Immigration, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Moakley/Deconcini Bill, 1984-87 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- U.S. Immigration/Refugee, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Refugee - Salvador, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Chile Immigrations, 1974-75 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Refugee Legislation, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Indian Studies (Cornell), 1984-85 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Indigenous, 1980s (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Minorities, 1970s-1980s (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous, 1970s-1980s (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Multinationals, 1970s-1980s (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Refugees, 1970s-1990s (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Refugees, 1970s-1990s (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Mexico- Ecumenical Committee of US citizens in Mexico, 1982-89 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Infomativo Grvpo De Apoyo Pervano, 1990-91 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Puerto Rico material, 1979-80 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Pledge of Resistance, 1988-92 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Puerto Rico Libre, 1976-78 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Venezuela Now, 1977-78 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Pledge of Resistance material, 1986-89 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Guatemala material, 1983-85 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Hunger in Third World Countries, 1976-81 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Peace newsletters- Central New York, 1986-90 (Box 6)
- Chile - newspaper clippings, publications, memos, correspondence, 1970s-1980s (Box 11)
- Chile - newspaper clippings, publications, memos, correspondence, 1970s-1980s (Box 12)
- Costa Rica, Honduras, Ecuador, Carribean, Paraguay, Mexico, Uruguay - newspaper clippings, publications, memos, correspondence, 1970s-1980s (Box 13)
- Dominica Republic, Colombia, Grenada, Venezuela, Haiti, Bolivia, Panama - newspaper clippings, publications, memos, correspondence, 1970s-1980s (Box 14)
- Human Rights in Chile- newspaper clippings, publications, memos, correspondence, 1970s-1990s (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Human Rights in Cuba- newspaper clippings, publications, memos, correspondence, 1970s-1990s (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Human Rights - general- newspaper clippings, publications, memos, correspondence, 1970s-1990s (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Human Rights and Military Funding- newspaper clippings, publications, memos, correspondence, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Amnesty International- newspaper clippings, publications, memos, correspondence, 1970s-1980s (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Human Rights - Nicaragua - newspaper clippings, publications, memos, correspondence, 1970s-1990s (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Council of Human Rights in Latin America - newspapers, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Inter-Church Committee on Human Rights in Latin America - Newsletter, 1970s-1980s (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Presente! - newsletter for the coalition for Justice in Central America, 1980s-1990s (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Central America - Central America Report and April 1982 copy of Central America Monitor, 1980s (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Central America - Central America Update, 12/1981-6/1987 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- The Network of Educators' Committee on Central America and Central America in the Classroom, 10/1988-3/1990 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Central America NewsPak, 1988-90 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Central America Post-Trip Packet, 1988-89 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Urgent Action Alert sheets and responses to letters, 1987-1989 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Amnesty International - Urgent Action Network, 1980s (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
- Central America- Madre Speaks, 1986-89 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Central America-Intereligious Task Force, 1984-89 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Central America - Labor Report, 1985-90 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Central America - Information Bulletin, 1986-87 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Central America - Information Bulletin, 1987-88 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Central America - Central America Report published by Inforpress Centroamericana, 1980-81 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Central America - Central America Report published by Inforpress Centroamericana, 1982-90 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Central America-Central America Bulletin, 1984-86 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Central America Bulletin, 1986-90 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- "The New Revolutionary Mood in Latin America" by Richard Shaull, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Central America - Historical Institute Update, 1983-88 (Box 17, Folder 11-12)
- Central America - General, 1980s-90 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Central America - US Policy, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Central America-Solidarity (Labor), 1980s (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Central America - US policy towards Central America, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Central America - Church, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 17)
- Central America - Church - right wing, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 18)
- Central America - Development and Economics, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 19-20)
- Central America - Government policies, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 21)
- Central America - Gov. policies (peace plan), 1988 (Box 17, Folder 22)
- Arias Peace Plan, 8/7/1987 (Box 17, Folder 23)
- Central America - Peace plan, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 24)
- Central America - Peace plan, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 25)
- Central America - Opposition, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 26)
- Central America - Women/Solidarity, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 27)
- Central America-Solidarity: Art and Culture, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 28)
- Central America - Solidarity, 1980s (Box 17, Folder 29)
- Environmental Project on Central America, 1987-90 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Certification, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Coalition Close-Up Newletter, 1979-1988 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- CISPES- US Committee in Solidarity with the People of El Salvador, 1984-90 (Box 18, Folder 4-6)
- Iran Contra, 1987-88 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- El Salvador Material, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Christic Institute, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Central American Health Rights Network, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Campaign for Political Rights - Organizing Notes - Newsletter, 1979 and 1980s (Box 18, Folder 11)
- American Friends Service Committee, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 12)
- FBI Investigations of CA Solidarity/CISPES, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 13)
- FBI Surveillance, 1987-88 (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Quest for Peace, 1980s-1990 (Box 18, Folder 15)
- SHARE Foundation (Box 18, Folder 16)
- NISGUA- Network in Solidarity with the People of Guatemala, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 17-18)
- Institute for Policy Studies, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 19)
- First Food, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 20)
- HAP-NICA - Humanitarian Assistance for Independent Agricultural Development in Nicaragua-Research material, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 21)
- MADRE, 1980s-1990 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- NISGUA - Network in Solidarity with the People of Guatemala, 1980s-1990 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Nicaragua Network Solidarity, 1980s (Box 19, Folder 3-6)
- COMADRES - Committee of Mothers and Relatives of Political Prisoners, Disappeared, Assassinated of El Salvador, "Monsignor Oscar Romero", 1980s (Box 19, Folder 7)
- US Organized Labor and Latin America, 1980s (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Peace Brigades International, 1980s-1991 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Regional Solidarity, 1986-1990 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Regional Pledge, 1986-89 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Buffalo Pledge, 1987-88 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Albany Pledge of Resistance, 1986-88 (Box 19, Folder 13)
- National Pledge, 1986-87 (Box 19, Folder 14)
- Pledge of Resistance - general information, 1980s-1990 (Box 19, Folder 15-16)
- PACCA- Policy Alternatives for the Caribbean and Central America, 1980s (Box 19, Folder 17)
- Veterans for Peace, 1980s (Box 19, Folder 18)
- Washington Office of Latin America, 1980-s (Box 19, Folder 19)
- Witness for Peace, 1980s-1991 (Box 19, Folder 20)
- ENFOPRENSA - News summaries concerning Guatemala, 1983-89 (Box 20, Folder 1-6)
- Noticias De Guatemala, 1980-85 (Box 20, Folder 7-10)
- Guatemala Update, 1984-90 (Box 20, Folder 11-12)
- Guatemala-Comite De Unidad Campesina, 1986-89 (Box 20, Folder 13)
- Guatemala-OSGUA newsletter - Organization in Solidarity with the People of Guatemala, 1986-90 (Box 20, Folder 14)
- News in Brief, 1986-88 (Box 20, Folder 15)
- Guatemala-Informador Guerrillero, 1982-85 (Box 20, Folder 16)
- Venceremos - newspaper, 1984-85 (Box 20, Folder 17)
- El Salvador Alert - newspaper, 1980-87 (Box 20, Folder 18)
- El Salvador Alert - newspaper, 1987-92 (Box 20, Folder 19)
- El Salvador - Senal De Libertad - magazine (Box 20, Folder 20)
- El Salvador - El Sol - newsletter, 1987-90 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- El Salvador - El Sol- newsletter, 1989-90 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- El Salvador Bulletin, 1982-83 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- El Salvador - Radio Farabundo Marti, 1988-90 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- El Salvador - Treinta Dos, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Guazapa - newspaper, 1983-86 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- El Salvador - Venceremos, Mar. 1989 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Madres - De Plaza De Mayo - newspaper, 1985-90 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Chilean Resistance Courier, 1970s (Box 21, Folder 9)
- Chile - Chile Net, 1987-90 (Box 21, Folder 10)
- Costa Rica - Friends Peace Center, 1987-89 (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Honduras - Honduras Hoy, 1985-87 (Box 21, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous periodicals, 1980s (Box 21, Folder 13)
- Caribbean material, 1980s (Box 21, Folder 14)
- Caribbean - US policy material, 1980s (Box 21, Folder 15)
- Guatemala - Secretaria de Ayuda A Refugiados Guatemaltecos, 1983-92 (Box 21, Folder 16)
- Bolivia - Informe R, 1984-87 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Colombia - Informe Colmbiano, 1982-87 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Honduras - Boletin Internacional, 1982-88 (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Natural Resources in Latin America - material, 1982-91 (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Latin America - Human Rights, 1979-90 (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Latin America - Government Policies, 1964-88 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Latin America: Development/Economics, 1969-90 (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Latin America - Solidarity, 1981-88 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Latin America: Indigenous/Solidarity, 1984-88 (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Latin America: Labor, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 10)
- Latin America: US Policy Toward, 1973-89 (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Latin America: Human Rights (Refugees), 1988 (Box 22, Folder 12)
- Latin America: Other Govt. Policy Toward, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 13)
- Latin America: Women, 1977-88 (Box 22, Folder 14)
- Latin America: Students, 1971-91 (Box 22, Folder 15)
- Latin America: Art and Culture, 1978-90 (Box 22, Folder 16)
- Latin America: Church/Solidarity, 1973-81 (Box 22, Folder 17)
- Latin America: Church- miscellaneous material, 1967-92 (Box 22, Folder 18-19)
- Latin America: Women in the Church, 1987-88 (Box 22, Folder 20)
- Andes - Development/Economics, 1977-79 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Andes - Music, 1980-90 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Jamaica - Economy/Dev.z, 1981-85 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Trinidad, 1976-80 (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Belize, 1981-85 (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Guyana, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Andes- Andean Focus, 1983-91 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Latin America: Working papers and pamphlets on various topics, 1972-89 (Box 23)
- Latin America - General, 1988-90 (Box 23, Folder 8)
- Latin America: Resource Center Bulletin, 1984-87 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- Latin America: Rapidas, 1979-89 (Box 23, Folder 10)
- Latin America: Washington in Focus, 1984-86 (Box 23, Folder 11)
- Perspectiva Mundial (Box 23, Folder 12-14)
- Lucha, 1975-78 (Box 23, Folder 15)
- Lucha, 1983-88 (Box 23, Folder 16)
- Latin America Update, 1977-90 (Box 23, Folder 17)